# Yuhan Mao

Tel: (+86) 18990202242 | Email: susanmao1997@gmail.com

## **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

I am interested in using machine learning techniques to understand human being. Research areas such as computational neuroscience, natural language understanding and generation are what I am willing to dive into. I am also keen on explorations in reinforcement learning.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON

London, UK

MSc Data Science and Machine Learning

Sep 2019 – Sep 2020

• Academic: Distinction

• Curriculum: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Graphical Models, Statistical Data Science, Numerical Optimization, Statistical Natural Language Processing

#### BEIJING INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Beijing, China

Bachelor of Engineering in Automation

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

• **Academic:** 90.1/100

• Curriculum: Linear Algebra, Probability and Mathematical Statistics, Mathematical Analysis, Computer Technology and Program, Practice on Program with C Language, Pattern Recognition, Functions of Complex Variables and Integral Transformation, Signals and Systems, Mathematical Logic and CPU, Automatic Control Theory and etc.

## **PUBLICATION**

• M. Yuhan, "A Novel Collaborative Filtering Algorithm Based on Trust," 2018 Eighth International Conference on Instrumentation & Measurement, Computer, Communication and Control (IMCCC), Harbin, China, 2018.

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Decoding from the Human Ventral Stream Using Deep Convolutional Networks

London, UK

Love Lab, University College London, Supervisor: Prof. Bradley C. Love

Feb 2020 - Sep 2020

- Aimed at exploring the relationships between the hierarchical structure of human visual system and convolutional neural networks
  - Bold5000 dataset is used to represent the human brain activities, since fMRI signals of Bold5000 are processed vectors that can represent brain activities of different regions after viewing a subset of pictures from ImageNet
  - VGG-16 is selected as the convolutional neural network to investigate, since it achieves good results in ImageNet competitions
- Used a projection layer to link the fMRI voxels of each brain region to each layer of VGG-16, trained the projection layer and compared the decoding results of different combination of brain region and VGG layer
- Added Gaussian noise to the data, and using some other techniques like spatial regularization to augment the
  dataset and improve the results

## Named Entity Recognition for Chinese Electronic Medical Records

Beijing, China

School of Automation, Beijing Institute of Technology, Supervisor: Prof. Yuan Li

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

- Processed the original Chinese Electronic Medical Records dataset into the format suitable for training and testing the models
- Used machine learning methods, including Conditional Random Field (CRF), as well as Bi-LSTM based
  models and other more complex models (Bi-LSTM+CNN+CRF) to predict the type of named entities and
  compared between different models and parameters to optimize the models
- Gathered results of different training models and finished a systematic thesis that discussed the effect of different models on the named entity recognition task based on Chinese Electronic Medical Records.

#### Chinese Ouestion Answering on DuReader with Pre-trained Contextualized Word Vector

London, UK

Course Project of Statistical Natural Language Processing, UCL, Lecturer: Prof. Sebastian Riedel Feb 2020 – Mar 2020

• Gathered and Pre-processed the Chinese-English and Chinese-Japanese parallel corpus, using attentionbased neural machine translation model to train the corpus and extract the contextualized vectors (CoVe)

# Yuhan Mao

Tel: (+86) 18990202242 | Email: susanmao1997@gmail.com

from the encoder

• Used R-Net, Match-LSTM and Bi-DAF to evaluate the results of different Chinese-English and Chinese-Japanese CoVe vectors, compared the results of the three models and tuned the models for better results.

## Thesis Classification System Based on Naïve Bayesian Model

Beijing, China

Course Project of Pattern Recognition, Beijing Institute of Technology, Lecturer: Prof. Qi Gao

Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

- Adapted theories in Natural Language Processing to design and implement the thesis classification system with Python and Scikit-Learn
- Gained a better understanding of basic algorithms in machine learning including Naïve Bayes, K-means, etc.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Shenzhen Institute of Advanced Technology, Chinses Academy of Sciences

Shenzhen, China

Oct 2020 – present

Position: Machine Learning Engineer at Material Center

- Apply machine learning methods to predict the properties of different materials
- Use machine learning methods to assist the design and exploration of new materials.

## INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

## Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing, China

Position: Machine Learning Intern at High Performance Computer Research Center

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

- Participated in image segmentation projects based on neural networks
- Learned about the Linux system and docker technology used in application
- Developed skills to apply deep learning frameworks to solve practical tasks.

WISESOFT CO., LTD

Chengdu, China

Position: Machine Learning Intern at Face Recognition Department

July 2018 - Aug 2018

- Used deep learning methods like convolution neural networks to develop face recognition and learned basic concepts of recurrent neural network.
- Had a systematic study about machine learning and deep learning, including the applications of PyTorch and Tensorflow.

## **SKILLS**

## **Programming Skills:**

- Languages: Python, C/C++, Julia, Matlab
- Machine Learning APIs: PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn and etc.

Languages: Mandarin, English

## HONORS AND AWARDS

- First-class Scholarship for Academic Excellence (GPA ranked Top 1 in major), School of Automation, Beijing Institute of Technology, 2019
- First-class Prize in China National College Students English Competition, 2017
- Second-class Prize in English Speech Contest, Beijing Institute of Technology, 2017
- Honorable Mention in COMAP's Mathematical Contest in Modeling / Interdisciplinary Contest in Modeling (MCM/ICM), 2017

## **ACTIVITIES**

## Student Union, Beijing Institute of Technology

Oct 2015 - Mar 2016

Member of Department of Art of Student Union, in charge of the organization of artistic activities.

## Academic Guidance Center, Beijing Institute of Technology

Oct 2015 – Jun 2016

• Member of Department Office, in charge of the arrangements of academic tutorial appointments.

# **Hi-World Youth Community**

Apr 2017 – Jun 2017

• English-Chinese translator, in charge of translating the propagating information concerning international communication activities that help youngsters build up stronger leaderships and academic abilities.